<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
	    <update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="Monk-Dynamis.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/AngryGuineaPig/AuroraBuilderCustomContent/main/AGPContent/Monk/Monk-Dynamis.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Way of Dynamis" type="Archetype" source="Reddit : Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS">
		<supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Way of Dynamis focuses on training their disciples in how to better utilize the energy generated by their movement. By manipulating the Ki within their bodies as they move, they store the energy that would otherwise be lost and convert it into devastating power that they release through their strikes. The process of sorting and expelling this energy is a closely guarded secret, as in untrained hands it can wreak havoc upon the user's body. Monks that undertake training in the Way of Dunamis often wear heavy gauntlets and boots whilst training to acclimatize their bodies to perform actions under increases stress before they are allowed to begin training in the secret techniques. The core principle of the Way of Dynamis is "If you are always willing to move forward, nothing can stand in your way."</p>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_FLOW" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_KINETIC_BLASTS" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_FLUX" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_CACHING_POTENTIAL" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_REALIZED" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The Way of Dynamis focuses on training their disciples in how to better utilize the energy generated by their movement. By manipulating the Ki within their bodies as they move, they store the energy that would otherwise be lost and convert it into devastating power that they release through their strikes. The process of sorting and expelling this energy is a closely guarded secret, as in untrained hands it can wreak havoc upon the user's body. Monks that undertake training in the Way of Dunamis often wear heavy gauntlets and boots whilst training to acclimatize their bodies to perform actions under increases stress before they are allowed to begin training in the secret techniques. The core principle of the Way of Dynamis is "If you are always willing to move forward, nothing can stand in your way."</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_FLOW" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_KINETIC_BLASTS" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_FLUX" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_CACHING_POTENTIAL" level="11"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_REALIZED" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Dynamis Flow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Reddit : Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_FLOW">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the ability to enter into a state known as Dynamis Flow, where you change your movement patterns to gather the continuous kinetic energy that would normally be lost when you move. You may spend 1 ki point to enter Dynamis flow, after which you generate one Kinetic Charge for every 10 ft of movement on your turn. You may have a maximum number of kinetic charges equal to half your monk level and you lose any charges at the start of your next turn. Dynamis flow lasts until the start of your next turn and you cannot use dynamis flow two turns in a row.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="ki">
			<description>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the ability to enter into a state known as Dynamis Flow, where you change your movement patterns to gather the continuous kinetic energy that would normally be lost when you move. You may spend 1 ki point to enter Dynamis flow, after which you generate one Kinetic Charge for every 10 ft of movement on your turn. You may have a maximum number of {{dynamis:charge}} kinetic charges and you lose any charges at the start of your next turn. Dynamis flow lasts until the start of your next turn and you cannot use dynamis flow two turns in a row.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dynamis:charge" value="level:monk:half" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Kinetic Blasts" type="Archetype Feature" source="Reddit : Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_KINETIC_BLASTS">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you can take the built up energy within you and release it in a devastating blast. Once per turn whilst in the state of Dynamis Flow, after gaining at least one Kinetic Charge you can choose to expend any Kinetic Charges you have generated when making an unarmed attack against a target, dealing an additional 1d4 force damage for each expended charge.</p>
			<p>Additionally, you cna cause the attack to expand outwards in a concussive blast. Regardless of whether you hit or miss the intended target you can spend 1 ki point to force each creature in a 15ft cone to make a constitution saving throw against your ki DC or take a number of d4s in force damage equal to the number of charges you expended.</p>
			<p>Any force damage dealt by Kinetic Blasts have the Siege ability dealing double damage to objects and structures.</p>
			<p>The force damage dealt by the Kinetic Blasts scales with the martial arts damage die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Ki">
			<description>At 3rd level, you can take the built up energy within you and release it in a devastating blast. Once per turn whilst in the state of Dynamis Flow, after gaining at least one Kinetic Charge you can choose to expend any Kinetic Charges you have generated when making an unarmed attack against a target, dealing an additional 1d{{martial arts:dice}} force damage for each expended charge.&#13;
			Additionally, you cna cause the attack to expand outwards in a concussive blast. Regardless of whether you hit or miss the intended target you can spend 1 ki point to force each creature in a 15ft cone to make a constitution saving throw against your ki DC or take a number of d{{martial arts:dice}}s in force damage equal to the number of charges you expended.&#13;
			Any force damage dealt by Kinetic Blasts have the Siege ability dealing double damage to objects and structures.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Dynamis Flux" type="Archetype Feature" source="Reddit : Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_FLUX">
		<description>
			<p>At 6th level you've refined your movement in Dynamis Flow to gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Flowing Movement.</b> While in Dynamis Flow, movement through difficult terrain costs you no extra movement.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Agile Flow.</b> Any attacks of opportunity made against you while in Dynamis Flow are made at disadvantage</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="ki">
			<description>At 6th level you've refined your movement in Dynamis Flow to gain the following benefits:&#13;
			Flowing Movement. While in Dynamis Flow, movement through difficult terrain costs you no extra movement.&#13;
			Agile Flow. Any attacks of opportunity made against you while in Dynamis Flow are made at disadvantage</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Caching Potential" type="Archetype Feature" source="Reddit : Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_CACHING_POTENTIAL">
		<description>
			<p>At 11th level you have learned to control the potential energy of your body as you remain still in order to make it more durable. When you use Patient Defense you gain resistance to bludgeoning, slashing and piercing damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>At 11th level you have learned to control the potential energy of your body as you remain still in order to make it more durable. When you use Patient Defense you gain resistance to bludgeoning, slashing and piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Dynamis Realized" type="Archetype Feature" source="Reddit : Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_RDDT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAY_OF_DYNAMIS_DYNAMIS_REALIZED">
		<description>
			<p>At 17th level you've perfected how energy flows through your body and are also able to extract the potential energy of those you halt and and devastate their body by converting it to kinetic energy. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Kinetic Ceiling.</b> The maximum number of charges you are able to hold doubles</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Realised Might</b> When you hit a creature with Stunning Strike and cause them to be stunned, you may add {{martial arts:dice}} force damage to every following unarmed strike make on that creature on that turn. On the last  hit, the target must make a strength save against your ki DC or be launched 30ft away. If the creatures path is blocked treat it as if the creature had been falling towards the blockage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Ki">
			<description>At 17th level you've perfected how energy flows through your body and are also able to extract the potential energy of those you halt and and devastate their body by converting it to kinetic energy. You gain the following benefits:&#13;
			Kinetic Ceiling. The maximum number of charges you are able to hold doubles&#13;
			Realised Might. When you hit a creature with Stunning Strike and cause them to be stunned, you may add 1d{{martial arts:dice}} force damage to every following unarmed strike make on that creature on that turn. On the last  hit, the target must make a strength save against your ki DC or be launched 30ft away. If the creatures path is blocked treat it as if the creature had been falling towards the blockage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dynamis:charge" value="level:monk:half" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>